var next_question=0;
var score = 0;
var change_questButtonElement;
var allQuestions = [
	{
		question: "1. What three countries are in North America?", 
		choices: ["Canada, United States and Mexico", "Mexico, Canada and Spain", "North America, Canada, United States"], 
		correctAnswer:0
	},
	{
		question:"2.  The state of Florida is what kind of landform?",
		choices: ["Mountain range","Peninsula","Hill"],
		correctAnswer:1

	},
	{
		question:"3.  The imaginary line that divides the globe into Northern Hemisphere and Southern Hemisphere.",
		choices: ["prime meridian","longitude","equator","grid"],
		correctAnswer:2
	},
	{
		question:"4.  Tiny model of Earth shaped like a sphere.",
		choices:["map","globe","hemisphere","meridian"],
		correctAnswer: 1
	},
	{
		question:"5.  Why do people set up systems of laws in their communities?",
		choices:["To find a better job in the community.","To go to a new school in the community.","To make the community safe.","To make the community unsafe."],
		correctAnswer:2
	},
	{
		question:"6.  Longitude lines travel north and south.",
		choices:["true","false"],
		correctAnswer:0
	},
	{
		question:"7.  How would you describe a rural community?",
		choices:["The towns are small and far away","The cities are big.","The towns have many people.","The towns have many schools."],
		correctAnswer:0
	},
	{
		question:"8.  Which landform makes it possible for people in the Western region to enjoy snow skiing?",
		choices:["plateau","desert","mountain","canyon"],
		correctAnswer:2
	},
	{
		question:"9.  The Earth has ______ oceans.",
		choices:["1","0","3","5"],
		correctAnswer: 3
	},
	{
		question:"10.  Imaginary lines that travel West and East are Longitude.",
		choices:["true","false"],
		correctAnswer:1
	}

];


function startQuiz(){
	var started_Button = document.getElementById("getStartedButton");
	started_Button.parentNode.removeChild(started_Button);
	changeQuestion();
	var change_questButtonText =  document.createTextNode("Next Question");
	change_questButtonElement =  document.createElement("div");

	change_questButtonElement.appendChild(change_questButtonText);
	document.getElementsByClassName("content")[0].appendChild(change_questButtonElement);

	change_questButtonElement.className = "nextButton";
	change_questButtonElement.onclick = changeQuestion;
	
}

function changeQuestion(){
	if(next_question > 0 ){
		var last_question = next_question - 1;
		if(document.quiz_Form.radio_options[allQuestions[last_question].correctAnswer].checked === true){
			score += 1;
		}
	}

	if(next_question === allQuestions.length){
		quizCompletion();
		return;
	}

	var current_question =  allQuestions[next_question];
	var question_text = current_question.question;
	document.getElementById("title").innerHTML = question_text;
	var radio_html = "";
	for (var i =0 ; i < current_question.choices.length;i++ ){
		radio_html += "<div class='radio-buttons'><input type='radio' id='" +current_question.choices[i]  +"' name='radio_options' value='" + current_question.choices[i] + "'/>"+ "<label for='"+ current_question.choices[i]+ "'>" +current_question.choices[i] + "</label> </div>";
	}
	document.quiz_Form.innerHTML = radio_html;
	if(next_question === (allQuestions.length -1)){
		change_questButtonElement.innerHTML = "Finish Quiz";
	}
	next_question += 1;

}

function quizCompletion(){
	document.quiz_Form.parentNode.removeChild(quiz_Form);
	change_questButtonElement.parentNode.removeChild(change_questButtonElement);
	var user_score = (score / allQuestions.length) * 100;
	document.getElementById("title").innerHTML = "Your Grade: " + user_score.toFixed(0) +"%";

	switch (user_score){
		case 0:
		case 10:
		case 20:
		case 30:
			var quiz_response = document.createTextNode("You need to go back to school! ASAP!");
			break;
		case 40:
		case 50:
		case 60:
			var quiz_response = document.createTextNode("Your should probably read Wikipedia more.");
			break;
		case 70:
		case 80:
			var quiz_response =  document.createTextNode("Someone watches the Discovery channel on their spare time.");
			break;
		case 90:
		case 100:
			var quiz_response =  document.createTextNode("You are as smart as a third grader! Congratulations!");
			break;
	}

	var quiz_responsElement = document.createElement("div")
	quiz_responsElement.appendChild(quiz_response);
	quiz_responsElement.className = "quiz-response";
	document.getElementsByClassName("content")[0].appendChild(quiz_responsElement);
	return;
}
